Hello and welcome to new episode of
what's cooking in Business Central. In
this episode, we will configure and show
you how to use external storage for your
document attachments. In order to
configure external storage for your
document attachments, you would need to
go and configure external file accounts.
You can configure external storage for
document attachments for any external
file account which you have whether it
is blob storage, file share or
shareepoint storage. In order to
configure it, you would need to go to
navigate and select file scenarios
then assign scenarios.
And here we have new scenario document
attachments external storage.
Here you would need to confirm that you
are using this feature as it is and on
your own risk because once the files are
offloaded it is your responsibility to
make proper backups and maintain those
files. If files get deleted on external
storage they will also not be available
anymore for business central
environment. Now a scenario is assigned
to file account. We would need to
configure this module further. So we
would need to click on additional
scenario setup either from file scenario
assignment or from the factbox on
external file accounts.
Upon executing action external storage
setup shows up and we can enable this
feature. After enabling this feature, it
is important that we set also root
folder for the storage. We can choose
the folder on top hierarchy or go inside
it and select any folder on it. Let's
select this folder.
Additional options which we have is
regards upload and delete policy. First
option here would be to choose whether
the files should be immediately deleted
after they have been uploaded to
external storage. If you enable this
feature, delayed after will be become
non-editable.
If you turn it off, you will be able to
put date formula inside it, which
represents for how long those files will
be kept in business central environment
before they get deleted. Together with
this option, scheduled upload should
also be enabled. This option
automatically offloads all your document
attachments from your database by
creating a job queue which will be run
each night at 100 a.m. by default and
offload your files. There is also option
to delete external files when
attachments are deleted. There are
scenarios when you want to delete the
file from business central environment
but keep it on external storage. If you
select this option, the file will remain
on external storage whether or not you
make destructive changes in Business
Central. Now we are ready to use this
feature. Let's go back to RO center page
and for example open some sales orders.
Select sales order and under document
attachments, select upload file. Just
drag and drop some files and they will
appear on the right side of the fagbox.
The files will be automatically
offloaded to external storage and based
on the setup they may be deleted from
business central environment or be
retained. To confirm that those files
have been offloaded, go back to external
file accounts under the file account
where the scenario is attached and go to
additional scenario setup and select the
action document attachments. Here you
will see uploaded document attachments
and see that boolean uploaded to
external is set to to true for those
files. Since we set up the date formula
to deleted files after 7 days, the
copies are kept in the business central
environment temporarily until they
expire. Additional features in this
module include storage sync which you
can use to offload existing document
attachments in your database to external
storage. A more likely scenario, once
all your document attachments are moved
to external storage, you can also bring
them back. Just select from external
storage and the system will download all
those document attachments back to
Business Central.